Vishal Pippirichetti

Java Developer

vishalpippirichetti@gmail.com • 9920781025 • Mumbai, Maharashtra

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-pippirichetti-840992173/

https://643384fdfc1ce10008ef7ae7-quiet-melba-401ad3.netlify.app/

Professional Summary

As an experienced Java developer focused on solving customer problems, improving usability, and maximizing efficiency using Java and J2EE technologies, specialization with a creating web application. effective at working in agile environments using Scrum methodologies

Skills

Core Java Collection JDBC Hibernate SpringBoot RestApi Microservices

ReactJS MySQL

Professional Experience

06/2022 - 11/2022

Systems Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services

Mumbai, India

- I worked on the "New Campus Portal" internal project.
- Participated in performance analysis, design, development and testing.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Implemented the backend business layers using Springboot and RestApi

01/2020 - 06/2022

Professional Product Developer, DXC Technology

Mumbai, India

- Participated in performance analysis, design, development, and testing.
- Worked closely with clients to establish specifications and system designs.
- Developed Java modules implementing rules and workflows using SpringBoot and RestAPI.
- All the functionality is implemented using Springboot, Hibernate and IPA.
- Implemented Data Access Layer(DAL) using Spring Data and Hibernate ORM tool.
- Worked on Java Collection API for handling the data objects between the business layer and frontend.

Education

06/2015 - 05/2019 Bachelor of Engineering: Information Technology,

Mumbai, India

Mumbai University CGPA: 7.20 /10.

06/2013 - 05/2015 **HSC,** The Andhra Education Society's Junior College

Mumbai, India

00/2013 = 05/2013

Percentage: 69.23

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my belief.